

getpatlau.com hello@getpatlau.com (604) 880-6606

I'm a interaction design student currently studying at the School of Interactive Arts and Technology. My passion lies in learning to solve problems, whether the problem be how a business workflow should feel to go through to what micro interactions delight children and the elderly alike.

skills

knowledge

Interaction Design User Experience Design Design and User Research Wireframing

technical skills

Photoshop HTML / CSS
Illustrator Java
InDesign JavaScript
Premiere PHP
After Effects C++ / C#

experience

UI/UX Designer

Visier Inc.

January 2014 - August 2014

Worked as a UI/UX Intern to help define and design the application's experience including workflow, transitions, and visual identity.

- Delivered well designed app elements and improved upon them by participating in design reviews and shares.
- Collected feedback from internal users to improve app experience.
- Created wireframes to prototype a workflows and utilized those to present possible solutions.
- Administered the visual design and development of an internal development project for a customer community portal.

Result: Contributions from my designs were implemented into the application's workflow, and the customer community portal launched within time specifications given. My experience at Visier has gotten me to make prototypes to address client needs upfront rather than work with theoretical designs.

learning

Design Evaluation SFU

January 2015 - May 2015

Learned how to approach evaluation of designs and user testing for design heuristics and experiences.

- Analyzed theoretical scenarios to improve existing designs and produced reports based on evidence found to prove the potential in the new design.
- Performed user tests which include interviewing participants and producing analytical data from user performance.
- Learned to how to filter data gotten from testing with users to improve designs.

Result: Created questionnaires, conducted interviews, and wrote evaluation reports that followed best practices to extract usable information from testing.



patrik lau

projects

Mobile App Development MagNote

May 2015 - July 2015

A small note and reminder application based around quick physical interactions with a user's phone.

- Prototyped a small application that made use of hardware sensors, service components for constant processing, and implementing standard user interface elements.
- Conceptualized a product idea from simple physical actions.
- Created workflows that emphasized the quickness of the design.

Result: Final prototype received an A grade for technical implementation. Experience from the technical side of development proved to be a important experience in communicating design ideas into technical specifications.

Game Design and Unity Drag-on Knight

September 2014 - December 2014

A short story lined platformer made in Unity. As a team we learned what is fun for our players and adjusted the gameplay mechanics to suit the experience.

- Wrote and implemented a fold-back storyline that allows for players to shape their experience within Drag-on Knight.
- Adjusted well known game mechanics to work with our intended player experience, examples being platforming motion controls and mouse based directional aiming.

Result: Player experience of Drag-on Knight over the development period changed from a simple straight forward game to a more challenging and interactive experience.

education

Simon Fraser University

September 2011 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Interactive Arts and Technology

about me



gaming and playing

Games are a challenge to play, good to enjoy, and rewarding to design.



cooking and feasting

I enjoy trying new things in the kitchen, which gets better with people to eat what I make.

I like to enjoy other people's stories and telling my own, trying out new activities, and bringing people together over food and conversation. Meeting new people and going new places is hard for me at first, but with experience I move quicker everytime.